广播电台播音员:一个圣诞节前夕的上午,00:11:05.我的同胞们,
Radio Announcer: 00:11:05 on a Christmas Eve morning.
明天的此时此刻,一切都会结束,当然买卖照常进行!
And by this time tomorrow fellow kiddies it
will all be over but the exchanging
音乐:叮叮当,叮叮当,叮……
Music: Jingle bell, jingle bell, jingle bell rock...
迈克:夹克外套.围巾.(闻了闻)蓝色的.衬衫.
Mike: Jacket.Scarf.(sniffs) Blue.All right.Shirt.Uh, long-sleeve.
呃.长袖的.样式不好.交易价22.50.
Uh, wrong style.Exchange value 22.50.
本:我的做一个,迈克!
Ben: Do one of mine mike!
迈克:本,我现在有点忙.
Mike: Oh Ben, I'm a little busy right now.
本:就一个!
Ben: Just one!
迈克:好吧.就一个.内衣.
Mike: Alright, ok, one.Underwear.
本:又来了?怎么就觉得我对内衣那么感兴趣呢?
Ben: Again?How am I supposed to have fun with underwear?
迈克:我不知道.反着穿.
Mike: I don't know.Wear it backwards.
本:换一个,迈克.
Ben: Do another Mike.
迈克:本,不愿意了?
Mike: Ben, do you mind?
我正在找压缩盘播放机.
I'm looking for the compact disc player that I've been hinting about.
本:就再来一个,求你了!
Ben: Just one more, just one more please!
迈克:好了,好了.袜子!
Mike: alright, alright, alright Socks!
本:袜子?你到底想干什么?
Ben: Socks?What the heck is going on around here?
麦琪:驯鹿!(笑)还有,星星,圣诞树和圣诞……胸罩?
Maggie: Ohhh, reindeer!(laughs) and a star, and a Christmas tree, and a Christmas, ummm, bra?
开萝尔:不,妈妈.这是个调制解调器.
Carol: No mom, it's a modem.
麦琪:调制解调器?
Maggie: A modem?
开萝尔:对,我一直都想得到这个东西,我电脑上用的.如果我有了它,这个圣诞节会是我讫今为止最愉快的圣诞节.
Carol: Yeah, the thing that I've been asking for my computer.The thing that if
I get will make this the happiest Christmas ever
杰森:麦琪,开萝尔,过来.看,比刚才下得更大了!
Dad: Maggie, Carol come here.Come look.It's snowing harder than before!
麦琪:多漂亮了啊!耶.我在想,
Maggie: Oh, isn't it beautiful??Yeah.I was thinking how perfect it is.
这是多么的完美啊.我有自己的家庭,一个漂亮的房子,
I have my family, a beautiful home, everybody's healthy.
全家所有人身体健康.太棒了,晚饭就要好了.今儿是圣诞夜,
Great, dinner's almost ready.It's Christmas Eve and it's snowing!
刚好还下雪!我不知道,我们还缺什么?
I can't think of a single other thing we need.
开萝尔:可能还需要一个调制解调器.
Carol: A modem might come in handy.
杰森:你不要太那个了,开萝尔!
Dad: Oh, not you too Carol.
开萝尔:我不要太哪个?
Carol: Not me too what?
杰森:好像你关心的唯一的事情就是是否能够得到自己相要的礼物.
Dad: Well, it seems like the only thing that you care about is whether
you get this present you want.
开萝尔:(尖叫)我只不过是说,
Carol: (shrieks) I was only commenting that if I'm lucky enough to get
如果我有足够好的运气得到一个调制解调器的话,
a modem for my computer,
我会非常非常愿意和妈妈分享它的便利,妈妈可以更好的写作,
I'd be more than willing to share it with Mom who could use it to write
可以通过它浏览整个世界上所有的数据库.
her stories by tying into virtually any database in the entire planet.
杰森:我怎么会那么错怪你呢?
Dad: How could I have misjudged you?
迈克:看!雪下得更大了.
Mike: Ah!Look at this!It's snowing harder.
麦琪:太漂亮了!
Maggie: I know isn't it beautiful?
迈克:漂亮??妈妈,路况越来越差了.
Mike: Beautiful??Mom, the roads are getting bad.
麦琪:迈克,圣诞夜你还需要去哪儿?
Maggie: Michael, where to you have to go on Christmas Eve that's more
还有比你家更重要的地方么?
important than your family?
迈克:不,我刚才是在想我亲爱的老爸.
Mike: Well no where, I was just thinking of my dear, old Dad
杰森:那他要去哪儿?
Dad: Where does he have to go?
开萝尔:哈里电脑音像城圣诞之夜欢乐大酬宾.
Carol: Crazy Harry's computer and stereo city Christmas Eve blowout.
杰森:那人给你们回扣了还是怎么着?
Dad: C'mon are you guys getting a kickback from this man or what?
本:我有个好消息.你们不是一直在说圣诞节真正的意义不在于圣诞礼物或者其它好东西么?
Ben: Ho ho ho.Boy have I got great news.
You know you guys have been saying the real meaning of Christmas has got
nothing to do with presents and other neat stuff?
杰森:我们一直在谈论的是,
Dad: We've been talking about how sharing and giving are more important
分享和给予为什么比索取更加重要?
than getting.
本:我是拐角那边的那家比萨饼店后边的垃圾桶里……
Ben: Yeah, well, I was in the dumpster behind the pizza place around the corner...
麦琪:等等.本,你在那儿里做什么?
Maggie: Uh, wait, wait wait.Ben, what were you doing in the dumpster?
本:给迈克买圣诞礼物.
Ben: Christmas shopping for Mike.
迈克:本,你的消息.
Maggie: Ben your news.
本:我碰到我这个小孩,然后我请她到家共进圣诞晚餐.
Ben: Well, I met this kid and I invited her home for Christmas Eve dinner.
杰森:你做了些什么?
Dad: What did you do?
本:我把她带回家所以我们大家可以分享给予的快乐.你好,小孩!
Ben: I brought her home so we can all share the joy of giving.Hey Kid!
开萝尔:妈妈,你肯定会把我的圣诞节搞砸的.
Carol: Mom, this is going to ruin my entire Christmas.
杰森:本,你太小了,还不能往家里带陌生人.
Dad: Ben you're just too young to be inviting strangers.
本:我们可以把所有的东西都给她,因为她一无所有.
Ben: We can give her everything because she doesn't have anything.
这难道不是个好主意么?
Isn't this fantastic?
杰森:本,我们觉得你应该明白一点,
Dad: Ben, we thought you understood that if any time a stranger should
如果有陌生人找什么理由接近你.
come up to you for any reason.
麦琪:你不应该和他们产生任何瓜葛.
Maggie: That you should have nothing to do with them
本:我知道.
Ben: I know.
麦琪:亲爱的,如果我们在城市里,
Maggie: Honey, when we're in the city and someone comes up to me and asks
有人向你走过来然后问你要钱,我会怎么做?
me for money what do I do?
本:您置之不理,继续走.
Ben: You keep walking.
麦琪:对.
Maggie: Right.
本:然后爸爸掏钱给他们.
Ben: and then Dad gives 'em the money.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:我们以后再说这件事.
Dad: We can talk about this later.
本,
Ben, the point is that, well,
问题的关键是这样的,如果你还是一个小孩子,
you're still a young boy and if somebody asks you for something,
这时有人管你要东西,
you're just too young to decide for yourself whether they're needy or
你太小还不足以独立判断得出结论他们是需要帮助的人还是危险的人.
dangerous.
本:但是她什么东西都没问我要.
Ben: But she didn't ask me for anything.
杰森:你们是怎么认识的?
Dad: Well, how did you meet her?
本:我踩到了她的脑袋.
Ben: I jumped on her head.
杰森:什么?
Dad: What?
本:在我就要进到垃圾筒里的时候……
Ben: Well, as I was getting into the dumpster...
杰森:本,她在垃圾筒里做什么?
Dad: Ben, what was she doing in the dumpster?
本:等着比萨饼屋的人扔比萨.
Ben: Waiting for the pizza place to throw out a pizza.
麦琪:天哪.
Maggie: Oh dear.
本:你知道那个胖家伙么?就是比萨饼店里的那个,
Ben: You know the fat guy at the pizza place with the funny mole on his
前额上有颗痣,痣上长撮毛?
forehead with the hair growing out of it?
他出来的时候说他已经报警了,
Yeah, well he came out and said he was calling the cops and since it was
因为当时下雪而她没有东西吃也没有地方呆,所以我请她到家里来.
snowing and she didn't have anything to eat or anyplace to stay,
换了你们,也会这样做的是么?
I invited her to come here.That's what you guys woulda done right?
杰森和麦琪:呃,也许,她,我们当中哪位……
Dad and Maggie: Well, I, uh maybe she, one of us..uh.
无家可归的女人:厕所在哪儿?
Homeless Woman: The john?
开萝尔:我们家没厕所.
Carol: We don't have one.
迈克:不.大厅尽走,你的左手边.
Mike: Uhh, no, it's down the hall and to your left.
开萝尔:你怎么能让她用咱家的卫生间?
Carol: How could you let her use our bathroom?
迈克:我又不用.
Mike: Hey, I never use that bathroom.
麦琪:她在哪儿?
Maggie: Where is she?
迈克:她不喜欢开萝尔那个样子所以她走了.
Mike: Uh, she didn't like the way Carol smelled so she left.
开萝尔:她在卫生间里.
Carol: She's in the bathroom.
麦琪:我去拿些纸巾.
Maggie: Oh, I better get some towels.
杰森:看起来,
Dad: Well, it seems as though Ben has presented all of us with quite a
虽然本给我们出了个不大不小的难题.
challenge.
迈克:对,准备怎么惩罚他,爸爸?
Mike: Yeah, what's going to be his punishment, Dad?
杰森:我不准备惩罚他.
Jason: Well, I'm not going to punish him.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
杰森:而且我们要留下她吃晚饭,过圣诞夜.
Dad: And the girl will be staying for dinner and spending the night.
开萝尔和迈克:什么?(注:大写.重音,强调)
Carol and Mike: WHAT?
开萝尔:算了吧,爸爸,成熟点吧.
Carol: Oh come on Dad, grow up.
迈克:爸爸,善良和愚蠢之间是泾渭分明的.
Mike: Hey Dad, there's a real fine line between being nice and stupid.
杰森:你们俩是从来学的这些想法?
Dad: Where do you two get these kind of ideas?
麦琪:消毒剂在哪儿?
Maggie: Where is the disinfectant?
杰森:麦琪.
Dad: Maggie,
麦琪:干么?
Maggie: Yes?
杰森:你能不能跟开萝尔和迈克讲一讲你对此事是怎么想的?
Dad: Would you explain to Carol and Mike how you feel about this?
麦琪:好.我同意你爸爸所说的,
Maggie: Oh, well, I agree with your Dad that we should share our dinner
我们应该和这位姑娘共进圣诞晚餐.
with this girl.
杰森:并且共渡圣诞之夜.
Dad: and let her spend the night.
麦琪:好了,麦琪,成熟点吧!你好!
Maggie: Oh, come on Jason, grow up!Hello!
杰森:我们还没有正式地互相介绍.我叫杰森,
Jason: Well, we haven't officially met.I'm Jason, this is Maggie.
她叫麦琪.这是开萝尔和迈克.
This is Carol and Mike.
这是本的哥哥和姐姐.
This is Ben's brother and sister.
无家可归的女人:本是哪位?
Homeless Woman: Who's Ben?
杰森:你在垃圾桶遇到的那个就是本.我俩的儿子.那您是?
Jason: Ben's the kid you met in the dumpster.Our son.And you are?
无家可归的女人:南希*里根(注
Homeless Woman: Nancy Reagan.
麦琪:你好,南希,很高兴见到您,终于见到您本人了,
Maggie: Well Nancy nice to finally meet you in person.Meet you in person.
终于见到您本人了.晚餐之前,还有时间,你可以好好洗一个热水澡.
Well, ok. Well, there's just enough time before dinner for a nice, hot shower.
无家可归的女人:继续.
Homeless Woman: So go ahead.
麦琪:你洗完澡之后,我有些衣服您换上,
Maggie: I have something for you to put on after your shower Mrs.Reagan.
里根太太.我会把您的衣服放到洗衣机里.
I'll just slip your clothes into the washer.
无家可归的女人:我不想麻烦您.
Homeless Woman: Umm, I don't want to put you out or nothing.
麦琪:哦,不不不,我会高兴这么做的.
Maggie: Oh no no no, it's my pleasure.
我的意思是,不会费很大工夫的,也就是漂洗几件……哦,
I mean how much trouble could it be to rinse out a couple of...oh thanks.
谢谢.(唱歌)鲁道夫,小驯鹿,红红的鼻子,
Oh I hope my washer has a yuck cycle.(singing) Rudolf the red nose reindeer,
闪亮闪亮的……刀子.哦,上帝.
had a very shiny...knife.Oh God.
杰森:亲爱的,我可以进来么?
Jason: Honey, can I come in?
麦琪:哦,请进来吧.
Maggie: Oh, please do.
杰森:我把孩子们给收买了,让他们去收拾桌子.
Jason: I bribed the kids to set the table.
杰森:亲爱的,对不起.我以后再也不收买他们了.你要干什么?
Jason: Honey, I'm sorry, I'll never bribe them again.What are you doing?
麦琪:哦,杰森.这是她的东西.
Maggie: Oh Jason.This belongs to her.
杰森:天哪.
Jason: Oh boy.
麦琪:亲爱的,我觉得乐善好施同样是一件美好的事情,而你呢,可爱,
Maggie: Honey, I think charity is wonderful too and you're a dear, sweet man,
温柔,但是,我们能帮助一个身上藏刀的人么?
but couldn't we help someone who doesn't pack a pig sticker?
杰森:冷静,不要小题大做.
Jason: Calm down don't get excited.
麦琪:你当然说起来容易些.
Maggie: Well, that's easy for you to say.
你受过专门的训练知道如何治疗精神错乱者.
You're trained to deal with disturbed people.
杰森:目前,你还不能确定这孩子是不是精神错乱者.
Jason: Now, you don't know that this kid is disturbed.
麦琪:杰森,她一个过活儿,
Maggie: Jason, don't you think the fact that she lives in filth and carries
生活无着,又生活在贫民窟里.你不觉得从她的生活环境可以看出一些问题的征兆么?
her own cutlery indicates a teensie-weensie problem?
杰森:亲爱的,
Jason: Honey, I have an awful lot of experience dealing with runaways
和收容所里的离家出走者打交道的经验我实在是太多了.
down at the shelter.
麦琪:我知道.
Maggie: I know
杰森:我明白他们非常孤独,非常绝望.
Jason: Well, I know that they're lonely and they're desperate.
麦琪:对.
Maggie: Yes.
杰森:而且非常恐惧.
Jason: And frightened.
麦琪:我也是啊!
Maggie: Me too!
杰森:好了好了,让我跟她说.
Jason: Alright then, let me talk to her.Trust me.
相信我.我向你保证,她不会从我这儿把刀拿回去的,
I can promise you one thing she won't get the knife back and if I sense
如果我感觉到任何危险,我会报告有关方面的.
any danger I'll call the authorities.
麦琪:好的.
Maggie: Ok.
杰森:看,我知道如果处理精神疾病患者.
Jason: You see, I do know how to handle disturbed people.
麦琪:不要太得意了.
Maggie: Ohhh, don't push your luck.
杰森:感觉好些了么?
Jason: Feel better?
无家可归的女人:干净点了.嗨!那刀是我的.
Homeless Woman: Cleaner.Hey!That's my blade.
杰森:我们还是希望客人不要全副武装为好.
Jason: Well we would prefer that our guests were unarmed.
无家可归的女人:好.把刀给我,我走.
Homeless Woman: Fine.Give me the knife and I'll split.
杰森:我们可以谈谈么?
Jason: Can we talk?
无家可归的女人:让我走好了.
Homeless Woman: Just let me leave.
杰森:坐下.
Jason: Sit down.
无家可归的女人:为什么?
Homeless Woman: Why?
杰森:因为我不希望看到你流落街头,
Jason: Well because I have a bit of a problem with the idea of you wandering
在圣诞之夜饥寒交迫.
the streets cold and hungry on Christmas Eve.
无家可归的女人:那么,你是一个民主主义者了?
Homeless Woman: So you're a democrat?
杰森:谈,或者,我把你交到有关方面?
Jason: Do you want to talk or should I call the authorities?
无家可归的女人:共和主义者.
Homeless Woman: Republican.
杰森:坐下.
Jason: Sit.
无家可归的女人:如果你想报警,更好,
Homeless Woman: If you are thinking of calling the juvies I've got better
比在这儿和某个有毛病的精神病医生儿磨牙强得多.
things to do than talking to some stupid shrink.
杰森:那么,今儿就是你的末日.
Jason: Well, then this isn't your day.
无家可归的女人:你什么意思?
Homeless Woman: What do you mean?
杰森:我就是个有毛病的的精神病医生儿.
Jason: I'm a stupid shrink.
无家可归的女人:天啊.世界上的垃圾桶千千万万,
Homeless Woman: Oh boy.
你家的孩子怎么就掉进了我藏身的那个桶.
Out of all the dumpsters in the world your kid had to fall into mine.
杰森:我看到周围并没有秘密警察,
Jason: Well I don't see any secret service people around so I'm going
所以我觉得你并不是真正的南希*里根.
to assume that you're not really Nancy Reagon.
无家可归的女人:阁下,你很棒.
Homeless Woman: Sir, you are good.
杰森:你为什么逃跑?
Jason: Why'd you run away?
无家可归的女人:我不喜欢新的电视剧.
Homeless Woman: I didn't like the new TV season.
杰森:如果大家不喜欢电视节目都像你一样跑出来,那么从这儿到丹佛市之间所有的垃圾筒都得满了.
Jason: Well if everybody who hated TV did that we wouldn't have an empty
你离开家的真正的原因是什么?
dumpster between here and Denver.Why did you really leave home?
无家可归的女人:因为大家都不希望我在那.
Homeless Woman: Because nobody wanted me there.
杰森:你父母是这么告诉你的?
Jason: Your parents told you that?
无家可归的女人:医生,让我替你省点时间吧.
Homeless Woman: Look, doc, let me save you some time.
没人打我,
Uhh, nobody hit me, nobody touched me, nobody did anything,
没人碰我,没有人做任何伤害我的事.
nobody gave a damn.
杰森:的确如此?
Jason: You sure?
无家可归的女人:看看,有谁会在意?我不再在乎这些了.
Homeless Woman: Look who cares?I don't anymore.
杰森:我不相信你.
Jason: I don't believe you.
无家可归的女人:那又怎么样?
Homeless Woman: So what?
杰森:如果你想用我们家电话的话,
Jason: So if you want to use our phone.
你可以不用告诉他们你是从哪儿打出的,就打个电话告诉他们你平安无事,
You don't have to tell them where you're calling from,
好么?
just make a call and let them know that you're still alive, ok?Ok.
无家可归的女人:你是要打电话给警察,是么?
Homeless Woman: You're going to call the heat now aren't you?
一定是这样,肯定是这样.
That figures, that just figures.
杰森:不,谁我也不打电话.
Jason: No, I'm not going to call anybody.You see, you're wrong about me.
看,你误会我了.如果你可能误会我的意思,
And if you could be wrong about me,
那么,你应该想一想这样一种可能,
you should consider the possibility that you could be wrong about your
就是你也可能误会你的家人.告诉你吧,在最近的三次选举中,
folks too.And for your information,
我没选民主党,也没有选共和党.
the last three elections I voted independent.
(唱歌)用冬青树的枝条妆扮起厅堂居室,fa la la la la ……
(singing) Deck the halls with bows of holly fa la la la la....
迈克:妈妈,妈妈,你能关小点声么?
Mike: Mom, mom, could you turn that down a little bit?
麦琪:等等.你是想要我把音响关小点么?
Maggie: wait, wait.You're asking me to turn the stereo down?
迈克:对.我知道对你来说那很重要,但是,我在这儿都快被吵死了.
Mike: Yeah, yeah, I know it's a first, but c'mon I'm getting fa la la
ed to death here
麦琪:没问题,迈克.我正好想放"海滩男孩"的圣诞专辑.
Maggie: No problem Mike.I'll just put on the Beach Boys' Christmas album.
迈克:不不,这个就很好.
Mike: no, no, this is fine.
麦琪:本,你不要看起来……
Maggie: Oh, Ben don't you look...
本:不用说了,妈妈.
Ben: Save it mom, this suit has weenie written all over it.
迈克:本,那个孩子在哪儿?
Mike: Hey Ben, where's the kid?
本:开萝尔正在试她那破衣服.
Ben: Carol's dressing her in some dippy outfit.
迈克:我只知道在我想吃点东西的时候,
Mike: All's I know is that she's not sitting next to me while I'm trying
她已经不在我身边了.
to eat.
杰森:为大胖猪让让地儿.
Dad: Make way for the big pig.
麦琪:这是最后一回.
Maggie: And this is the last of it.
迈克:妈妈,爸爸刚才怎么叫你呢难道你没有听到么?
Mike: Hey mom, you should have heard what dad just called you.
本:咱们开吃吧!开吃!开吃!
Ben: Let's eat!Let's eat!Let's eat!
杰森:谁……是不是少了开萝尔,还有我们的客人?
Jason: Whoa..aren't we missing Carol and our guest?
开萝尔:……我发誓!你们不会相信这是真的.
Carol: ...I swear!You guys are not going to believe this.
所有人:哦-----
Everyone: Ooohhhh.
麦琪:你看起来太美了!杰森,她很漂亮,是不是?
Maggie: Don't you look wonderful!Jason, doesn't she look beautiful?
本:看起来还不赖.
Ben: She doesn't look dippy ...
杰森:对不起,是你踢的么,本?
Jason: I'm sorry was that you I kicked, Ben?
麦琪:你为什么不跟本坐一块?
Maggie: Why don't you sit next to Ben.
本:你闻起来味道也很好.
Ben: You even smell good.
无家可归的女人:我几乎已经忘记垃圾桶了.
Homeless Woman: I hardly miss the dumpster.
杰森:借节日喜庆的气氛,我想提请你们注意希佛家多年以来伟大的传统,我们要围绕着餐桌告诉所有其它人为什么我们心存感激.
Jason: On that festive note,
I would like to remind you all of the great Siever family tradition where
we go around the table and tell everyone tells everyone else why they're
so thankful.
迈克:爸爸,每年我们做的都是这个!
Mike: Dad, we do this every year!
杰森:如果你们希望放弃……
Jason: Well, if you would rather just forget it...
孩子们:耶!
Kids: YES!
杰森:没人保佑你们.好了,本,你开始.
Jason: you're out of luck, ok.Alright now Ben you start.
麦琪:来了,本.
Maggie: C'mon Ben.
本:好吧,我心存感激之情是因为我今年长高了而迈克没有.
Ben: Alright, I'm thankful that I got taller this year and Mike didn't.
杰森:就这个?
Jason: That's it?
本:对,我也很高兴看到那次意外没有造成过多的损害.
Ben: Oh yeah and I'm glad there wasn't too much damage from the goofy
换了谁都一样,都会发生的.
glue incident.Could have happened to anyone.
麦琪:开萝尔!
Maggie: Carol
开萝尔:好.我非常高兴,
Carol: Ok.Well I'm glad that I got straight A's for the seventh year in
a row.And I'm also pretty pleased that Bobby Winett finally called me
是因为博比 *维耐特在终于在三个星期之后来看我,同时我也为我们全家人身体健康感到高兴.
after three weeks and I'm very happy that my whole family is healthy.
麦琪:宝贝,真美妙.
Maggie: Oh, honey, that's sweet.
开萝尔:至少听起来是的.
Carol: At least physically.
无家可归的女人:有意思.
Homeless Woman: It was funny.
杰森:迈克,该你了.
Jason: Alright Mike your turn.
迈克:从何说起呢.
Mike: Where to begin.
好.
Hahaha no, ok, I'm thankful for my car even though upkeep and routine
我心怀感激,因为我的汽车,
maintenance has gone through the roof lately which can drain a teenager's
虽然维修费和日常维护最近居高不下---我的兼职收入和几乎所有的余钱都填了进去……
part time job and virtually wiping out any extra...
杰森:迈克……
Jason: Mike...
迈克:爸爸?
Mike: Yeah dad?
杰森:没事.醒醒,麦琪!
Jason: Never mind.You're up Maggie!
麦琪:好好.我心怀感激之情,因为的孩子们,
Maggie: Ohh, okay well let's see.
我的职业,所有这些都归功于这个全美最富有智慧,最性感的家伙.开玩笑呢.
I'm thankful for my kids and my career and I owe it all to the smartest,
不,亲爱的,我说的是真的.
sexiest guy in the whole US of A.I'm just kidding.No honey, I'm serious.
杰森:好了,该我了.
Jason: Alright, it's my turn.
迈克:这样下去得磨蹭到明年了.
Mike: This could take us into New Year's.
杰森:好.
Jason: Well, I'm thankful that the Siever's made it through another year
我心怀感激之情,因为希佛一家人又渡过了一年,
without any major disasters,
没有大病大灾;同时,
with the exception of the goofy glue incident and I'm thankful that our
我心怀感激之情,因为我们的生活充满了(让迈克闭嘴)快乐.
lives are so full of (shut up Mike) joy.
我心怀感激之情,
And I'm thankful that we have a guest in our home this year who will go
还因为今年我们家来了一们小客人,她即将重新回到自己的世界,
back out into the world and tell the people that the Siever's worst crime
告诉那里的人们希佛家最大的恶就是他们是一群有些傻傻的但却是充满浪漫主义精神的人.
is that we're a little corny.
所有人:耶!
Everyone: Yeah!
麦琪:开始用餐.
Maggie: Let's eat.
本:等会儿!等会儿!
Ben: Wait a minute!Wait a minute!
南希*里根也要告诉我们她心怀感激的理由.
Nancy Reagon has to tell us what she's thankful for.
无家可归的女人:我没有什么可说的.
Homeless Woman: I got nothing to say.
杰森:那好吧.
Jason: That's okay.
迈克:不不.
Mike: No, no, no it's not,
我觉得如果我们把她当作家庭的一分子,
I think that if we're supposed to treat her like a member of the family
她会为我们所做的罪恶所感到羞愧.
that she should suffer the same humiliation that we do.
杰森:好了,咱们算了吧.
Jason: Let's just forget about it.
本:但是,爸爸你说过她……好吧,这回是谁踢的我?
Ben: But dad you said she...oh alright, who kicked me this time?
无家可归的女人:好吧……本,我心怀感激,
Homeless Woman: Oh ok.Uh...
因为你发现我并带我离开了垃圾桶,还有,
Ben I'm thankful that you fished me out of the garbage and Mrs.
希佛太太谢谢你给我洗了衣服,
Siever thank you for washing my clothes and Carol thank you for lending
开萝尔谢谢你把衣服借我穿.我心怀感激,
me your outfit.And I'm thankful that I'm not freezing to death in the snow.
因为在这场大雪中这没有冻死.至少是今天没被冻死.
For one day at least.
本:一切都挺好的,就那次意外看起来挺愚蠢的.
Ben: Gee, amongst all that the goofy glue incident seems pretty silly.
麦琪:注意了,看……桌.
Maggie: Watch out for the...the table.
杰森:哇!
Jason: Ow!
麦琪:杰森,你发觉了么,
Maggie: Jason, do you realize this is the first year that the kids are
今年是孩子们在圣诞早上注定会有惊喜发现的一年?
actually going to be surprised on Christmas morning?
杰森:关于阁楼是一个天才的设想.很高兴这主意是我想的.
Jason: The attic was a stroke of genius.I'm glad I thought of it.
你想没有想过,我们有的是不是太多了点?
Honey, does it ever occur to you that we just have too much?
麦琪:耶,我们很幸运.
Maggie: Yep.We sure are lucky.
杰森:看看所有这些.我们给开萝尔的.
Jason: I mean look at all this.To Carol from us.To Ben from us.
我们给本的.本给我们的.
To us from Ben.
麦琪:迈克赠开萝尔.迈克赠迈克?
Maggie: To Carol from Mike.To Mike from Mike?
杰森:看看这个.开萝尔赠南希*里根.
Jason: Look at this.To Nancy Reagon from Carol.To Nancy from Ben.
本赠南希.亲爱的,看哪.
Honey, look at these.
麦琪:不用看了.这是南希给迈克的.
Maggie: I don't have to.This is to Nancy from Mike.
杰森:他们没花时间去购物啊.
Jason: Well, they didn't have time to shop.
麦琪:你能相信这个么?
Maggie: Can you believe this?
杰森:我们的孩子更多地了解了圣诞节;要不,
Jason: Well, either our kids are learning something about Christmas or
就是我们更多地了解了我们的孩子.
we're learning something about our kids.
无家可归的女人:谁问他们的?到底是谁问他们的?
Homeless Woman: Well, who asked 'em?Who the hell asked 'em?
本:啊!不,爸爸,不,迈克!
Ben: Ahhhhhh!!No dad, no Mike!
杰森:怎么了,什么事?
Jason: What is it, what's wrong?
本:看!
Ben: Well, look!
杰森:哦,不.
Jason: Oh no.
麦琪:她席卷一空.
Maggie: She took everything.
麦琪:甚至我的袜子和内衣!
Ben: Even my socks and underwear!
迈克:告诉我.
Mike: Alright, just tell me this.
你还没有把礼物从楼阁上收下来吧?
Had you brought the good presents down from the attic yet?
杰森:迈克,现在不是只想你自己的时候.
Jason: Mike, this is no time to be thinking of yourself.
迈克:好,昨天是时候,
Mike: Well yesterday was a time for that, just before Mr.
就在惹事精(注:指Ben)把那个女强盗带回家之前.
Goofy glue, here, brought the cat burglar home.
开萝尔:好大的骗局!
Carol: What a rip off!
迈克:我们被人算计了?
Mike: Boy are we suckers.
麦琪:迈克,你就别说了.
Maggie: Michael just stop it.
杰森:真是不敢相信.我跟她谈过的.
Jason: Well, I can't believe it I mean I was talking to her.
我觉得我跟她有一定程度的沟通.
I thought I was getting somewhere with her.
迈克:对,现在她带着我们的圣诞节跑的无影无踪.
Mike: Yeah, well now she's getting somewhere with our Christmas.
我去追她.
I'm going after her.
本:我也去.
Ben: Me too.
麦琪:外面你们又能找到什么?
Maggie: You're not going to find anything outside...
本:哇!
Ben: Wow!
麦琪:你都了解到些什么?杰森……
Maggie: What do you know?Jason...
开萝尔:她不可能一直都这样.
Carol: She couldn't go through with it.
迈克:等她平安到家的时候她就不这样了.
Mike: She stopped when she was home free.
开萝尔:也许是她有些害怕.
Carol: Maybe she was scared..
麦琪:或者不好意思……
Maggie: Or sorry...
本:或者善良.
Ben: Or nice.
杰森:或者我们感染了她,就像她感染了我们一样.
无家可归的女人:嗨,爸爸……这是丹尼斯.对,真的是我.呃,我很好.你呢?圣诞快乐!
00:22:39,800
Jason: Or maybe she was just as affected by us as we were by her. Homeless Woman: Hi Daddy...it's Denise.Yeah, it's really me.Umm, I'm fine.How are you?Well Merry Christmas to you!